*   [6\. Prescription Deliveries (Not Available on Instacart White Labels)](#otnotice-section-647d4b00-812a-4137-93af-424523da0f7e)
*   [7\. Restaurant Orders (Not Available on Instacart White Label Sites)](#otnotice-section-41199132-97ce-473b-985e-43b7c840e6f9)

*   [6\. Prescription Deliveries (Not Available on Instacart White Labels)](#otnotice-section-647d4b00-812a-4137-93af-424523da0f7e)
*   [7\. Restaurant Orders (Not Available on Instacart White Label Sites)](#otnotice-section-41199132-97ce-473b-985e-43b7c840e6f9)

Privacy Policy

Last updated:  January 15, 2026

This Privacy Policy explains how Maplebear Inc. d/b/a Instacart and Maplebear Canada Inc. (“**Instacart**,” “**we**,” or “**us**”) collect, use, and share your Personal Information in providing services, including any Instacart websites, mobile apps, devices, APIs, white-label retailer websites or apps (“**Instacart White Labels**”) where this Privacy Policy is linked (the “**Services**”). “**Personal Information**” is any information that we can reasonably use to identify you. 

**Summary Notice:** 

*   We collect Personal Information as described in the “[Information We Collect](#otnotice-section-06f0417d-c301-4b27-9d62-2a850f9e81a8) [](#otnotice-section-06f0417d-c301-4b27-9d62-2a850f9e81a8)” section below.
*   We describe the business and commercial purposes for which we collect that information below under “[Information Uses](#otnotice-section-8d1bcbb1-5c8a-4b53-a5f1-ea24e1c79b74).”
*   We describe our disclosures of Personal Information, including why and to whom we make them, below under “[Information Disclosures](#otnotice-section-98259a16-f184-46ea-9dd3-a9ebf568c38b).” 
*   We describe choices and rights you may have with respect to our use and disclosure of your Personal Information, including with respect to how we sell or share certain categories of Personal Information, and how you may exercise these rights, including your right to opt out, under “[Your Privacy Choices](#otnotice-section-7a345332-a714-4524-a7e2-0f6bb5e9485e)[](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/policies/a8797342-d101-4396-b90e-665be5a6eacb?context=eyJkc1BvcnRhbElkIjoiY2QxYTBjNDEtYTUwNS00NjQyLWJiN2UtYTdhMjc4NjViYmZmIn0=#section-header-13).“
*   To help you better understand the practices described in this Privacy Policy, we have provided a table format that summarizes the information under “[Summary Table](#otnotice-section-f211ae28-ee93-49a6-a49e-7d6abefcbd15)[](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/policies/a8797342-d101-4396-b90e-665be5a6eacb?context=eyJkc1BvcnRhbElkIjoiY2QxYTBjNDEtYTUwNS00NjQyLWJiN2UtYTdhMjc4NjViYmZmIn0%253D#section-header-5)"  

**Table of contents:**

1.  [Information We Collect](#otnotice-section-06f0417d-c301-4b27-9d62-2a850f9e81a8)
2.  [Payment Processors and Partners](#otnotice-section-da275df2-ad8a-4b44-8a5b-3ee999c0089f)
3.  [Information Uses](#otnotice-section-8d1bcbb1-5c8a-4b53-a5f1-ea24e1c79b74)
4.  [Information Disclosures](#otnotice-section-98259a16-f184-46ea-9dd3-a9ebf568c38b)
5.  [Summary Table](#otnotice-section-f211ae28-ee93-49a6-a49e-7d6abefcbd15)
6.  [Prescription Deliveries (Not Available on Instacart White Labels)](#otnotice-section-647d4b00-812a-4137-93af-424523da0f7e)
7.  [Restaurant Orders (Not Available on Instacart White Label Sites)](#otnotice-section-41199132-97ce-473b-985e-43b7c840e6f9)
8.  [Children’s Privacy](#otnotice-section-51467604-1347-4ab3-9b0c-1b88eb86f8cf)
9.  [Third-Party Websites](https://www.instacart.com/privacy#otnotice-section-89683500-6853-4ad0-b607-200736b8e30a)
10.  [Information Security](#otnotice-section-51467604-1347-4ab3-9b0c-1b88eb86f8cf)
11.  [Cross-Border Transfers](#otnotice-section-c8d4c4d5-bd2d-4edc-84fa-2b2a5dfc04a6)
12.  [Information Retention](#otnotice-section-47f07923-7130-49af-a650-8a26f0bbacf7)
13.  [Your Privacy Choices](#otnotice-section-7a345332-a714-4524-a7e2-0f6bb5e9485e)
14.  [Supplemental Disclosures for Residents of California](#otnotice-section-5ee63a88-2bb5-4d73-9010-0c9cf549cdc0)
15.  [Disclosures for Residents of Nevada](#otnotice-section-23162657-6908-48be-a9af-e5a5f3a8e187)
16.  [Disclosures for Residents of Canada](#otnotice-section-61598bf2-9fbd-43bb-accf-32dba57eab26)
17.  [Changes to this Privacy Policy](#otnotice-section-628508ec-44da-47d4-95c6-20d8e3a3d5ce)
18.  [Contact Information](#otnotice-section-a57c72e4-400e-4d51-8f82-be2f74ffa5eb)  

1\. Information We Collect
--------------------------

1.  **Information You Provide**   
    We collect the following Personal Information directly from you:
    *   **Contact information**. When you use or interact with the Services, we collect relevant contact details from you, including your name, telephone number and email address.
    *   **Account information**. When you set up an Instacart account, we collect your username and password, and other relevant information we request. 
    *   **Order information**. If you place an order through the Services, we collect information necessary to fulfill the order, including your delivery address, the date and time of the order, the items you ordered and any special instructions.
    *   **Age and identity verification information**. If you order alcohol, prescriptions, or other age- or dollar amount restricted orders, we collect information from your government ID to verify your age or your identity, including the government ID number and state or country, and, when legally required, a copy of the full state ID card. 
    *   **Vehicle information**. For curbside pickup orders, we may collect your vehicle license plate number(s).
    *   **Payment information**. If you place an order through the Services, we collect your billing address and method of payment. Additional details regarding the processing of your payment information can be found [below](#otnotice-section-da275df2-ad8a-4b44-8a5b-3ee999c0089f).
    *   **Fresh Funds**. If you participate in a Fresh Funds program and enter a Fresh Funds code to redeem your Fresh Funds credits, we collect information necessary for us to administer the program, including the name of the Fresh Funds partner in whose program you participate, your Fresh Funds balance, and the products you purchased with your Fresh Funds.
    *   **Personal shopper interactions**. When you place an order for delivery, you may communicate with your personal shopper via the Services about product replacements and other questions you or your personal shopper may have regarding the order. We collect the information contained in those communications.
    *   **Information you make public**. If you post in a public space on the Services or otherwise choose to make your Personal Information public on the Services (e.g., by sharing a recipe publicly on the Services), we collect such information. If you choose to share Personal Information publicly through the Services, please understand that we cannot control the actions of third parties who may access or collect this information. 
    *   **Customer service interactions**. If you interact or communicate with our customer service representatives, we collect the information you provide during such interactions.
    *   **Other information**. We collect any other information that you choose to provide during your interactions with our Services, including your responses to surveys that you choose to participate in (for example customer satisfaction surveys) or information that you provide directly to us regarding an experience with one of our retailers.
    *   **Information about other people**. In some cases, you may provide information to us about other people. For example, you may refer a friend to Instacart or send an Instacart gift delivery or gift card to someone. In these cases, we collect the recipient’s name, email, and delivery address, as applicable. You may also participate in Family Accounts and provide us information about your association with another Instacart customer. When you provide someone else’s information via the Services, you are responsible for ensuring that you have permission to share their information with Instacart. You may not provide Personal Information about children under the age of 18.
2.  **Information Collected by Automated Means**   
    When you use and interact with the Services, such as when you browse our website or use our app, we automatically collect certain information about your device, browser, and activity:
    *   **Browser and activity information**. When you access the Services, we collect information about your activity and interactions with the Services. This includes the products with which you engage or place in your cart, information related to your orders, the pages that you navigate to, and the frequency and duration of your use of the Services. We also collect information regarding your interactions with our chat bots, emails, texts, notifications, or other marketing from us (e.g., whether you opened or clicked). 
        *   We also may use third party services that employ software code to record users’ interactions with the Services. Session replays include users’ clicks, mouse movements, scrolls, and keystrokes/key touches during those sessions. These replays help us diagnose usability problems and identify areas for improvement.
    *   **Device information**. Our servers will record information about the computer, phone, or other device you use to connect to the Services. This includes information such as your device’s IP address, your device type, browser information (such as browser type and any settings), internet service provider, mobile network carrier, mobile country code, operating system, and unique device identifiers. We may also generate new unique identifiers using existing user device information. 
    *   **Location information**. When you access the Services, we may collect information about your device’s location in different ways: 
        *   _General location_. We infer your general location (such as country, region, or city), for example by using your device’s IP address. We rely on this general location to maintain security and prevent fraud (for example, detect suspicious or unusual access patterns), present localized experiences (such as content availability), comply with regional laws and obligations (for example, consent/opt-out prompts and notices), and to measure and improve our services through aggregated analytics. IP-based geolocation may be approximate and can reflect the location of your internet service provider or a VPN endpoint.
        *   _Precise geolocation_. If you choose to allow the Services to access location services through the permission system used by your device’s operating system or browser, we may collect the precise location of your device. We use your location information to facilitate the prompt hand-off of pickup orders (where available), to improve the accuracy of deliveries, to assist you in finding nearby stores for which pickup or delivery are available, and for other similar purposes. We may also use such information for our analytics purposes and to better understand how we can improve the Services. You can choose whether or not your device’s location information is shared with us by adjusting the settings on your device or browser, or when prompted by the Instacart application. 
    *   **Cookies, pixels, and other tracking technologies**. When you visit or otherwise interact with our Services, we (and our partners, advertisers, and third-party advertising networks) may automatically collect information about you using device identifiers, cookies, pixels, tags, application programming interfaces (“**APIs**”), software development kits (“**SDKs**”) and similar technologies. We use this information for various purposes, including to make the Services function properly, understand how you use the Services, personalize your experience, and measure, monitor, manage, display, and customize the advertisements you see.
3.  **Information Received From Other Sources or Parties**   
    We may receive Personal Information about you from other sources or parties. For example: 
    *   **Single Sign-on services**. Certain of our Services allow you to login using your credentials from a third-party platform, for example, using your Facebook or Google logins. If you log in to the Services through these third-party platforms, then depending on your settings on these platforms, we may receive some information about you from them, including your name, email address, device identifier and other identifiers.
    *   **Retailers**. We may receive Personal Information from our retail partners in whose loyalty programs you participate, such as a confirmation of your loyalty member status, to enable you to receive your loyalty benefits, discounts, and special promotions.
    *   **Prescriptions**. Certain Services allow you to place an order to have your prescriptions delivered to you from your pharmacy. If you use the Services for prescription delivery, the pharmacy processing your prescription will provide us with your name, delivery address, email address, birth date, telephone number, the total amount (including sales tax, where applicable) being charged to you for the prescription drug product(s) purchased, the prescription number(s) and in some case the total number of refills and your refill count (if you select to have refills fulfilled through Instacart). The pharmacy will also share whether the prescription drug product you have ordered requires temperature control. Additionally, if a prescription drug product delivered to you through the Services has been recalled, the pharmacy will share your name, email address, the date of the prescription drug product order, and the total amount to be refunded to you with us. 
    *   **Our Vendors and Business Partners**. We may also receive information, including contact, account, order, payment, and activity information, from our vendors and business partners, including the following:
        *   _Service providers and other vendors_. We receive Personal Information from our service providers and other vendors that we engage to perform services for us, including those that provide market research, delivery services, map services, email, or SMS communication platforms, or who assist us with providing, operating, or maintaining parts of our Services. This also includes our vendor who processes and fulfills your restaurant orders that are linked to your Instacart account.
        *   _Instacart partners_. Partners who have implemented or integrated certain Instacart services on their websites or applications may also let us collect information about your use of their sites or applications or share such information with us. This includes websites or applications that use Instacart’s APIs through which users can create or access their Instacart accounts and Instacart experiences that are embedded in a partner’s application. For example, if you use an Instacart Shoppable Recipe button on another site, we will receive information about your use of that button and of the third-party website or application. 
        *   _Marketing and Advertising partners_. We receive Personal Information about you, including advertising identifiers, contact information, browsing activity and related data about you from other parties, to supplement the information we collect, and from partners with whom we work for advertising measurement, analytics, and attribution.
            *   Co-branded partners. Partners with whom we operate co-branded businesses, offer co-branded products.
            *   Payment partners. We receive payment information from our payment providers, processors and partners (see [below](#otnotice-section-da275df2-ad8a-4b44-8a5b-3ee999c0089f)[](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/policies/a8797342-d101-4396-b90e-665be5a6eacb?context=eyJkc1BvcnRhbElkIjoiY2QxYTBjNDEtYTUwNS00NjQyLWJiN2UtYTdhMjc4NjViYmZmIn0=#section-header-2)).
        *   Fraud and dispute partners. We may receive Personal Information about you from partners who assist us in fraud prevention or in connection with claims or disputes.
        *   Instacart personal shoppers. We may receive Personal Information about you from Instacart personal shoppers in connection with your delivery, including information about your address and delivery details.
    *   **Other Parties**. We also may collect or receive Personal Information relating to you from:
        *   Other Instacart Services account owners. If other Instacart Services account owners invite you to place orders or request other services through their accounts, such as Family Accounts or Instacart Business Accounts, we collect information about your activities on those accounts.
        *   Other Instacart customers, if they refer you to our Services, send you a gift or other order delivery through our Services.
        *   Law enforcement, public health, and other governmental authorities.
        *   Publicly available sources.

2\. Payment Processors and Partners
-----------------------------------

When you pay for orders using a credit card or other payment method on our Services, your credit card or other payment information is collected and processed by our third-party payment processors. For example, if you pay with a credit card, the payment information that you provide through the Services is transmitted directly to our payment processor. We may receive certain information about your payment card from our payment processors, such as the last 4 digits of your card number and its expiration month and year. Certain Services allow you to place restaurant orders. Where available, if you place a restaurant order, our restaurant partner will collect and process your credit card or other payment information in order to fulfill the order. 

We also make available opportunities to pay for orders via other payment partners that may redirect you to their websites to submit your payment information. For instance, if you use an online payment system provider to make purchases through the Services, you will be directed to their websites to provide your payment information. These payment providers’ privacy policies apply to the information you provide to them through their website. 

3\. Information Uses
--------------------

We use the Personal Information we collect or otherwise obtain about you for the following purposes:  

*   **Provide and manage the Services**. We use your Personal Information in connection with the provision, administration, and management of the Services, including the operation of our websites and mobile applications. 
*   **Process your transactions**. If you place an order through the Services, we will use your Personal Information to process your payment and facilitate the delivery of your order. This may include information provided to us by our payment processors and partners, as explained above.
    
*   **Provide customer support**. We use your Personal Information to respond to your customer support communications and inquiries and assist you in your use of the Services.
    
*   **Communicate with you**. We use your Personal Information to provide you with relevant information about us or our Services (including details about our community affairs efforts) or to request information or feedback. These communications include sending you, from time-to-time, important updates about the Services, communications about changes to this Privacy Policy or other applicable terms and policies. 
    
*   **Carry out our marketing and provide you with targeted advertising**. We use your Personal Information to send you marketing and promotional materials and communications, including interest-based and other advertisements, and to analyze and measure their effectiveness. We may conduct these activities using device identifiers, cookies, pixels, tags, APIs, SDKs and similar technologies. Details on how to exercise your choices with respect to marketing and interest-based advertisements can be found in [Your Privacy Choices](#otnotice-section-7a345332-a714-4524-a7e2-0f6bb5e9485e)[](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/policies/a8797342-d101-4396-b90e-665be5a6eacb?context=eyJkc1BvcnRhbElkIjoiY2QxYTBjNDEtYTUwNS00NjQyLWJiN2UtYTdhMjc4NjViYmZmIn0=#section-header-13) below. 
    
*   **Customize and personalize the Services**. We use your Personal Information to help us understand which parts of the Services are of most interest to you and customize or personalize your experience. Based on how you browse, use, or otherwise interact with the Services, we display content, advertising, recommendations, digital coupons and otherwise personalize the Services to you. 
    
*   **Identify usage trends and improve the Services**. We use your Personal Information to help us (or our service providers and partners) conduct research and analytics about your use of the Services and identify usage trends. We also use your Personal Information to identify issues, test new features or changes in our features, and improve the Services.  
    
*   **Maintain security and prevent fraud**. We use your Personal Information to (a) help maintain the security and integrity of the Services, (b) detect, prevent, investigate, and protect you, our business, our users, and others from fraud, unauthorized transactions, and other unsafe activity, and (c) protect the safety, rights, or property of any person, the public, or Instacart.
    
*   **Satisfy our legal obligations**. We use your Personal Information to comply with applicable laws and regulations, respond to legal process, and/or respond to requests and communications from law enforcement authorities or other government officials. 
    
*   **Corporate Transactions**. We use your Personal Information to carry out sales and business transactions in which information held by us is among the assets transferred or is otherwise relevant to the evaluation, negotiation or completion of the transaction.
    
*   **Community Affairs** (not applicable to Instacart White Labels). Instacart is active in local communities as part of our mission to create a world where everyone has access to the food they love and more time to enjoy it together. We may use your information in connection with our community affairs efforts.
    
*   **As otherwise necessary or appropriate**. We will use your Personal Information for other purposes at your direction or with your consent. 

Please note that we may combine Personal Information that we collect (as described above) with information from other sources and use the combined information for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. 

In some circumstances we may deidentify Personal Information in accordance with applicable laws or receive such information from a third party and treat that deidentified data as non-Personal Information; in such cases, we will maintain and use the information in deidentified form and will not attempt to reidentify the information unless permitted by applicable laws. 

4\. Information Disclosures
---------------------------

We may disclose your Personal Information to the categories of recipients listed below. The specific Personal Information we may share with the categories of recipients listed below depends on how you interact with our Services. For instance, browsing our Services without an account involves different information collection and disclosure practices than activities like creating an account, placing orders, or seeking customer support.

*   **Affiliates and subsidiaries**. We may disclose your Personal Information to our affiliates, subsidiaries, and other companies under common control and ownership for purposes consistent with this Privacy Policy and other business and operational purposes.  
    
*   **Service providers and vendors**. We disclose your Personal Information to our service providers and vendors who provide services to us, for example cloud storage services, system hosting services, research partners such as those who provide customer research and surveys, data security services, delivery services, legal services, map services, email or SMS communication services, or other vendors that assist us with providing, operating or maintaining parts of our Services. 
    
*   **Instacart partners**. We also share your Personal Information with Instacart partners whose services we have integrated into our own, or those who have integrated certain Instacart services into their sites or applications, such as your contact and order information. These integrations may also let us collect information about your use of these partners’ sites or applications with us. 
    
*   **Payment processors**. We use payment processors as described [here](#otnotice-section-da275df2-ad8a-4b44-8a5b-3ee999c0089f)[](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/policies/a8797342-d101-4396-b90e-665be5a6eacb?context=eyJkc1BvcnRhbElkIjoiY2QxYTBjNDEtYTUwNS00NjQyLWJiN2UtYTdhMjc4NjViYmZmIn0=#section-header-2)[](https://docs.google.com/document/d/1z6e2nDV9zIWKqCLQepPpgb0xhXuNKh2i/edit#heading=h.qgav57nyj0fq), and disclose your Personal Information to such payment processors when you place an order through the Services.
    
*   **Fraud prevention partners**. To help protect our customers and prevent fraudulent purchases, we disclose your Personal Information (such as your device and activity information and order history) to our third-party fraud prevention providers so they can check whether the purchase is legitimate. 
    
*   **Marketing and advertising partners**. We may disclose your Personal Information (such as contact information, device information, browser and activity information, and general location) to our marketing and advertising partners, including social media platforms, third-party advertising networks, other websites and publishers, and other parties so we can both market our products to you and provide advertising services to other companies (e.g., to assist in serving and measuring our or their advertisements). 
    
    *   Some of our advertising partners may use cookies, SDKs, or other trackers to collect information about your online activity over time and across different websites or online services. This means that you may see advertisements while using the Services that are tailored to you, or you may see advertisements for Instacart on other online services, based on your use of the Services or your browsing behavior across other online services. For more information on choices you may have with respect to these technologies, see [Your Privacy Choices](#otnotice-section-7a345332-a714-4524-a7e2-0f6bb5e9485e)[](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/policies/a8797342-d101-4396-b90e-665be5a6eacb?context=eyJkc1BvcnRhbElkIjoiY2QxYTBjNDEtYTUwNS00NjQyLWJiN2UtYTdhMjc4NjViYmZmIn0=#section-header-13)[](https://docs.google.com/document/d/1z6e2nDV9zIWKqCLQepPpgb0xhXuNKh2i/edit#heading=h.bhfp3d99k8ra) below.
        
*   **Analytics providers**. We use third-party analytics providers who may deploy cookies, pixels, and similar technologies to analyze traffic to the Services and understand the usage of the Services as well as the performance of advertisements. Such providers may collect device, location, browser and activity information. For example, we use Google Analytics, an analytics tool that helps us understand how our customers engage with the Services. To learn more about Google Analytics’ data practices, please visit [Google’s support page](https://support.google.com/analytics/topic/2919631?hl=en&ref_topic=1008008).
    
*   **Personal shoppers**. If you place an order through the Services, we will disclose your Personal Information to the personal shopper who will pick it up and deliver it to you. Such information includes order information, delivery preferences, name, address and precise geolocation. Please note that the shopper will no longer have access to your Personal Information once your order has been delivered. 
    
*   **Retailers**. 
    
    *   Instacart Services Generally. We may disclose your Personal Information to our retailers to provide and maintain the Services. For example, we may disclose your order information to a retailer with whom you placed an order so their personnel can prepare your order for your shopper, a courier or for you to pick-up. We may also disclose your Personal Information to retailers to enable us to verify your participation in their loyalty programs or to obtain your loyalty number where you do not submit it to us directly. This enables us to make sure you see loyalty pricing if available and that eligible purchases are credited to your loyalty account. In certain cases, we may be required by law to provide certain of your information to our retailers. For example, if available in your region, when you buy alcohol using the Services, we may be required by law to share certain information with the retailer who makes the sale, including name, delivery address, government-issued ID information, the quantity, brand, price, proof, and volume of the alcohol purchased.
        
    *   Instacart White Labels. If you use an Instacart White Label Site, we may share with the retailer information collected from your interactions on that White Label Site, including your contact information, your order details, and information that we combine from other sources.
        
*   **Restaurant orders** (not applicable to Instacart White Labels). We disclose your Personal Information in connection with your restaurant orders as further detailed in [](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/policies/a8797342-d101-4396-b90e-665be5a6eacb?context=eyJkc1BvcnRhbElkIjoiY2QxYTBjNDEtYTUwNS00NjQyLWJiN2UtYTdhMjc4NjViYmZmIn0=#section-header-7)[Restaurant Orders](#otnotice-section-41199132-97ce-473b-985e-43b7c840e6f9) below.
    
*   **Fresh Funds Partners** (not applicable to Instacart White Labels). If you participate in our Fresh Funds program, we share with the Fresh Funds partner in whose program you participate your Fresh Funds balance, the products you purchased, and other information in connection with the program.
    
*   **Co-Branded products partners**. We operate businesses and offer services or sell product lines jointly with third-party businesses (such as co-branded credit cards) and we may share your Personal Information with companies that offer co-branded services or products.
    
*   **Other users of the Services**. We may disclose your Personal Information to other Instacart Services account owners and users of the Services if you choose to make such information public or select sharing features on the Services. For example, if you share a recipe publicly on the Services, the recipe, along with your first name and last initial, will be viewable by other users. In addition, if you select to participate in a Family Account or Instacart Business, the account owner who invited you to participate and the other participants will see some of your information and carts. 
    
*   **In connection with legal matters**. We may share your information when we believe that the disclosure is reasonably necessary or appropriate under, or to comply with, applicable laws, regulations, legal processes, or legal requests. In such cases, we share information that is relevant to the legal matter.
    
*   **Third parties in connection with a sale or business transaction**. We may sell or purchase assets during the normal course of business. If another entity acquires us or any of our assets, information that we have collected may be transferred to such entity and its advisors leading up to and/or following the transaction. In addition, if any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding is brought by or against us, Personal Information that we hold may be considered an asset of ours and may be sold or transferred to third parties.
    
*   **Other third parties**. We will disclose your Personal Information to other parties at your direction or with your consent. We may also disclose your Personal Information to other parties if we believe it necessary or appropriate either: (a) to protect our operations and those of any of our affiliates; (b) to protect our rights, privacy, safety, or property, and/or those of others; or (c) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit damages that we may sustain.   

We may disclose your Personal Information for other reasons that we will describe at the time of information collection or prior to sharing your information.

5\. Summary Table
-----------------

The table below provides a summary of 

*   the categories of Personal Information we have collected in the past twelve (12) months, 
    
*   the sources from which we’ve collected the information, and 
    
*   the categories of recipients to whom we may have sold Personal Information or with whom we may have “shared” Personal Information for cross-context behavioral advertising or targeted advertising.

As detailed in Section 4 [above](#otnotice-section-98259a16-f184-46ea-9dd3-a9ebf568c38b)[](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/policies/a8797342-d101-4396-b90e-665be5a6eacb?context=eyJkc1BvcnRhbElkIjoiY2QxYTBjNDEtYTUwNS00NjQyLWJiN2UtYTdhMjc4NjViYmZmIn0=#section-header-4)[,](https://docs.google.com/document/d/1z6e2nDV9zIWKqCLQepPpgb0xhXuNKh2i/edit#heading=h.1m3cgovof1wg) we also disclose some or all categories of Personal Information listed in the table below to our vendors, partners, service providers, contractors (e.g., our personal shoppers) and the other recipients listed above for various business purposes, including to operate, secure, improve, and market our Services, to fulfill orders and process transactions, to allow business partners to integrate with our Services, for co-branding, and to support customer service and analytics. The specific categories of Personal Information we disclose to these recipients depend on how you interact with us, the Services you use, the features you choose, and the nature of the services the recipient of the data provides to us.                 

| Category of Personal Information (and examples) | Source(s) | Categories of third parties to whom we may have sold/shared your Personal Information or to whom we have disclosed Personal Information for targeted advertising |
| --- | --- | --- |
| **Identifiers**<br><br>Example: Name, Email address, Phone number, Physical address, IP address and device identifiers, Loyalty program numbers | Directly from individuals <br><br>Through automated means <br><br>Third-party sources | Advertising and marketing partners<br><br>Analytics providers |
| **Personal Information categories listed in the California Customer Records statute** <br><br>Example: Telephone numbers, Payment information (credit card information) | Directly from individuals <br><br>Through automated means <br><br>Third-party sources | Advertising and marketing partners |
| **Characteristics of protected classifications under California or federal law**<br><br>Example: Gender | Directly from individuals | Advertising and marketing partners<br><br>Analytics providers |
| **Commercial Information**<br><br>Products you purchased or considered, Purchase history, Preferences and interest profiles, Consuming tendencies, Reviews<br><br>  <br><br>This also includes Payment information, including Payment card details, Digital wallet information, Gift card numbers, Account status and transaction details | Directly from individuals <br><br>Through automated means <br><br>Third-party sources | Advertising and marketing partners<br><br>Analytics providers |
| **Internet/Network Activity**<br><br>Your browsing and search history, Clickstream data, App usage, Interactions with the Services, emails, chatbots and advertisements, Session replay, and similar information | Through automated means <br><br>Third-party sources | Advertising and marketing partners<br><br>Analytics providers |
| **Geolocation Data**<br><br>Approximate location data | Directly from individuals <br><br>Through automated means | Advertising and marketing partners <br><br>Analytics providers |
| **Audio, electronic, visual, or similar information**   <br>Customer service call recordings, Chat transcripts, Training recordings, Customer-uploaded information | Directly from individuals <br><br>Through automated means | N/A |
| **Inferences**<br><br>Your preferences, behaviors, interests, and characteristics drawn from other Personal Information, including past orders or browsing history <br><br>We do not use any inferences to make legal or other significant decisions affecting you (as such term is understood under applicable laws) | Through automated means <br><br>Third-party sources | Advertising and marketing partners<br><br>Analytics providers |
| **Sensitive Personal Information** <br><br>Depending on your interaction with the Services, we collect government-issued IDs, Log-in information for accounts in combination with passwords allowing access to the accounts, Precise geolocation, Race/ethnicity, and Medical information | Directly from individuals <br><br>Through automated means | N/A |

6\. Prescription Deliveries (Not Available on Instacart White Labels)
---------------------------------------------------------------------

If you use the Services for a prescription delivery, we collect information from the pharmacy processing your prescription as described in [Information We Collect](#otnotice-section-06f0417d-c301-4b27-9d62-2a850f9e81a8)[](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/policies/a8797342-d101-4396-b90e-665be5a6eacb?context=eyJkc1BvcnRhbElkIjoiY2QxYTBjNDEtYTUwNS00NjQyLWJiN2UtYTdhMjc4NjViYmZmIn0=#section-header-1) above. Some of this information that we collect about you in connection with your prescription delivery may relate to: (i) your past, present or future physical or mental health or condition; (ii) the provision of health care to you; or (iii) your past, present, or future payment for the provision of health care (“**Personal Health Information**”). This Section governs our use and disclosure of your Personal Health Information. If there is a conflict between the terms of this Section and any other terms of this Privacy Policy or the Instacart Terms of Services, the terms in this Section will govern.

To the extent that we receive, create, maintain, use, or disclose any of your Personal Health Information, we will maintain the privacy and security of such information as required by applicable law, including the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act and the regulations promulgated under that Act (“**HIPAA**”). 

If you reside in the U.S., your Personal Health Information is protected under HIPAA and state law (depending on your state of residence). These laws give you rights with respect to the access, use, and disclosure of Personal Health Information by your health care providers, such as pharmacies, and us. When you place a pharmacy order using the Services, the pharmacy responds as we have described above in the “Information Collection” section by disclosing to Instacart your status as a patient of the pharmacy, and in some cases your prescription refill information. Information concerning your status as a patient of the pharmacy is protected by HIPAA. For a more complete description of your rights under HIPAA and the uses and disclosures of your Personal Health Information, please refer to your pharmacy's Notice of Privacy Practices. We will not disclose your Personal Health Information without your prior written consent with other people or non-affiliated companies unless: (i) such disclosure is necessary in order to provide the Services; (ii) to your pharmacy on their instruction, (iii) the Personal Health Information has been “de-identified” so that it cannot identify you; (iv) such disclosure is required by law; or (v) such disclosure is in connection with a business transaction or bankruptcy proceeding.

7\. Restaurant Orders (Not Available on Instacart White Label Sites)
--------------------------------------------------------------------

To make the restaurant experience available to you on Instacart, we share certain of your Personal Information with our restaurant partner who facilitates the restaurant experience for Instacart and allows Instacart to deliver restaurant-related content and offers on our Services. When you place a restaurant order, our restaurant partner will collect and process your credit card or other payment information in order to fulfill the order. Our restaurant partner may use certain of your information in order to provide the restaurant services, including to provide customer support, and will also disclose this information to the couriers and restaurants from which you placed an order so they can prepare and hand your order directly to you or to the courier who will deliver it to you. Your restaurant orders are linked to your Instacart account, and you can request information about those orders by exercising your Privacy Choices below. 

8\. Children’s Privacy
----------------------

We understand the importance of protecting the privacy of children, especially in the online environment. The Services are not designed for or intentionally directed to children under the age of 18. If we become aware that we have received Personal Information from an individual under the age of 18, we will take reasonable steps to remove the individual’s Personal Information from our records.     

9\. Third-Party Websites
------------------------

Some links on the Services may redirect you to third-party websites and services that we do not operate. We may also offer social sharing tools that let you share actions on the Services with other websites and vice versa. The privacy practices of these websites and services will be governed by their own privacy policies. We encourage you to review and understand their privacy policies before disclosing any Personal Information to them. 

10\. Information Security
-------------------------

We employ and maintain reasonable administrative, physical, and technical measures designed to safeguard and protect Personal Information under our control from unauthorized access, use, and disclosure. 

In addition, when we collect, maintain, access, use, or disclose your Personal Health Information, we do so using systems and processes consistent with information privacy and security requirements under applicable federal and state laws, including, without limitation, HIPAA. Nevertheless, because no data transmission or storage system is completely secure, we cannot guarantee the security of your information. 

11\. Cross-Border Transfers
---------------------------

Instacart operates a global business, and we use vendors located around the world to help us run our business. Accordingly, the disclosures described above may result in the transfer of your Personal Information outside of the country or region in which you reside. For example, the Personal Information of customers located in Canada will be transferred outside of Canada (and for residents of Quebec, outside of Quebec), including to the United States. 

When we transfer your Personal Information outside of your country or province of residence, we do so in accordance with applicable law and take appropriate steps to ensure your information is protected. However, please note that while outside of the jurisdiction in which you reside, some of your Personal Information will be subject to applicable local laws, which may permit government and national security authorities in those jurisdictions to access your Personal Information in certain circumstances. 

12\. Information Retention
--------------------------

We keep Personal Information only for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes for which we have collected it, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements. 

To determine the appropriate retention period for Personal Information, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the Personal Information; the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of the Personal Information; the purposes for which we use the Personal Information; whether we can achieve those purposes through other means; and the applicable laws that require us to retain information for regulatory purposes or permit us to retain the information to preserve our legal rights. 

13\. Your Privacy Choices
-------------------------

Depending on your place of residence, under applicable law, you can make certain choices and exercise certain rights with respect to our use of your Personal Information. Please note that rights and requests may be subject to applicable exceptions. We will not discriminate against you if you decide to exercise these rights.

1.  **Y****our Marketing Choices** 

We may send you periodic marketing and promotional emails, push notifications and/or text messages to your mobile device and, where required by law, we will obtain your consent to do so. If you no longer wish to receive our marketing and promotional communications, you may opt out of receiving them by following the opt-out instructions included in any communication that you receive from us or by visiting your Account Settings. Please note that even if you opt out of receiving marketing and promotional communications from us, we may still send you administrative and transactional messages from which you cannot opt out.    

2.  **Correct or Update your Account Information and Settings** 

If you have created an account through the Services, you may review, correct, or update your information (including your name, telephone number, delivery address, and payment information) at any time by logging in to your account and visiting the “Account Settings” page. Please note that changes to your settings may require some time to take effect. If you do not have or no longer have access to your Instacart account, please email us at [customerprivacy@instacart.com](mailto:customerprivacy@instacart.com) to submit your requests.

3.  **Other Privacy Rights**

Depending on where you reside, you may have certain additional privacy rights with respect to your Personal Information, under applicable law. The exact scope of these rights may vary by state and include certain exceptions:  

*   **Right to Know**what categories of data we have collected about you, the categories of sources of this data, and the categories of third parties to whom we disclose your information (as described above in this Privacy Policy).      
    *   Residents of certain states may have additional information rights, such as the right to request categories or specific third parties to which we disclose or sell Personal Information or share it for targeted advertising. If you reside in a state that allows for these additional disclosures, we will provide such information as part of your Right to Access request.  
*   **Right to Access** and obtain a copy of your Personal Information in a portable format. 
*   **Right to Correct** inaccurate Personal Information we hold about you.
*   **Right to Delete** the Personal Information we hold about you.
*   **Right to Opt Out** of sale and sharing of your Personal Information or disclosure of your Personal Information for targeted advertising.

4.  **How to Exercise These Privacy Rights**

To exercise these Privacy Rights, please follow the instructions below:

*   **Right to Opt Out** - you may exercise your right to opt out, where available, by visiting this [link](https://www.instacart.com/accounts/your-privacy-choices?msockid=1633c79115e2696918a3d10d14706827). You may also exercise your opt out rights by enabling a browser-based opt-out preference signal that complies with applicable laws, such as the Global Privacy Control (“GPC”). We listen for and honor GPC signals as required under applicable laws. To learn more about GPC, please click [here](https://globalprivacycontrol.org/).
*   All other Privacy Rights -
    *   **For Account Holders**. If you have an active Instacart account, click [here](https://www.instacart.com/user_privacy/authenticate) to submit a request. You will be prompted to re-log in to your Instacart account.
    *   **For Non-Account Holders**. If you do not have an Instacart account, no longer have access to your Instacart account, or you used Instacart through one of our embedded partner experiences (such as Groceries Powered by Instacart), please email us at [customerprivacy@instacart.com](mailto:customerprivacy@instacart.com) to submit your request.
    *   **Authorized Agents**. Depending on where you reside, you may authorize another person or entity to exercise certain rights on your behalf (an “Authorized Agent”). In such states, Authorized Agents can submit all eligible privacy requests on behalf of consumers by emailing us at [customerprivacy@instacart.com](mailto:customerprivacy@instacart.com). Authorized Agents may also click [here](https://www.instacart.com/accounts/your-privacy-choices?msockid=1633c79115e2696918a3d10d14706827) for instructions on opting out.

To protect the confidentiality of your Personal Information and that of others, we will only process your request for access, deletion and correction when your identity has been verified (or where otherwise not permitted). If your request was submitted by an Authorized Agent, where permitted or necessary to maintain security, we may require written proof of the Authorized Agent’s permission to submit the request on your behalf and may confirm the request directly with you (other than for opt-outs).  

5.  **Right to appeal**

If you submit a request to exercise any of the rights described above and we do not take action on the request, you may appeal our decision if you are in an eligible jurisdiction. To appeal a refusal to take action on your request, please email us at [PrivacyAppeals@instacart.com](mailto:customerprivacy@instacart.com) with the subject line “Rights Request Appeal.” If you are unsatisfied with the way that we have handled your appeal, you may have the right to complain to your state’s attorney general.

6.  **Do Not Track**

“Do Not Track” (“DNT”) is a developing standard for web browsers that aims to inform the websites you visit that you do not want information about your online activity collected over time and across third-party websites or online services. Although we do our best to honor the privacy preferences of our users, we do not interpret or respond to DNT or other similar signals from your browser at this time. For more information, visit [http://www.allaboutdnt.com](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/).

14\. Supplemental Disclosures for Residents of California
---------------------------------------------------------

The California Consumer Privacy Act (“**CCPA**”) provides California residents with certain rights, as described [above](#otnotice-section-7a345332-a714-4524-a7e2-0f6bb5e9485e)[](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/policies/a8797342-d101-4396-b90e-665be5a6eacb?context=eyJkc1BvcnRhbElkIjoiY2QxYTBjNDEtYTUwNS00NjQyLWJiN2UtYTdhMjc4NjViYmZmIn0=#section-header-13)[](https://docs.google.com/document/d/1z6e2nDV9zIWKqCLQepPpgb0xhXuNKh2i/edit#heading=h.nkicp2a2nske). Please refer to our Summary Chart in this Privacy Policy for details regarding the categories of Personal Information that we collect and sell or share for cross-context behavioral advertising as required under the CCPA. 

1.  **Use and Disclosure of Sensitive Personal Information**   
    We only use or disclose sensitive Personal Information as necessary to provide the Services; resist malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal actions directed at our business; ensure the physical safety of natural persons; and verify, maintain, and improve the quality of our Services. 

2.  **Consumer Affairs**   
    Under California Civil Code Section 1789.3, California residents are entitled to the following specific consumer rights notice: If you have a question or complaint regarding our website, please send an email to [legal@instacart.com](mailto:legal@instacart.com). You may also contact us by writing to us at the address provided below under [Contact Information](https://docs.google.com/document/d/1z6e2nDV9zIWKqCLQepPpgb0xhXuNKh2i/edit#heading=h.crgpk1huxhej). California residents may reach the Complaint Assistance Unit of the Division of Consumer Services of the California Department of Consumer Affairs may be contacted in writing at 400 R Street, Suite 1080, Sacramento, California 95814, or by telephone at (916) 445-1254 or (800) 952-5210.
3.  **“Shine the Light” Disclosures**  
    If we disclose information subject to California’s “Shine the Light” law to third parties for their own direct marketing purposes, California residents may opt out [here](https://www.instacart.com/accounts/your-privacy-choices?msockid=1633c79115e2696918a3d10d14706827).

15\. Disclosures for Residents of Nevada
----------------------------------------

If you live in Nevada, you can opt out of the sale of your personal information by completing the privacy request form [here](https://www.instacart.com/accounts/your-privacy-choices).

16\. Disclosures for Residents of Canada
----------------------------------------

For information about the transfer and storage of your Personal Information outside of Canada, or if you are a resident of Quebec, outside of your province of residence,  please see [Cross-Border Transfers](#otnotice-section-c8d4c4d5-bd2d-4edc-84fa-2b2a5dfc04a6)[](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/policies/a8797342-d101-4396-b90e-665be5a6eacb?context=eyJkc1BvcnRhbElkIjoiY2QxYTBjNDEtYTUwNS00NjQyLWJiN2UtYTdhMjc4NjViYmZmIn0%253D#section-header-11)[](https://docs.google.com/document/d/1z6e2nDV9zIWKqCLQepPpgb0xhXuNKh2i/edit#heading=h.qbu27ybatf4k) above.

For some of the uses described in Information Uses above, we may use technological tools that render decisions about you automatically. These include tools that detect fraud, which may lead to account deactivation.

If you are a resident of Canada, you may submit an access or deletion request as explained in [Your Privacy Choices](#otnotice-section-7a345332-a714-4524-a7e2-0f6bb5e9485e)[](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/policies/a8797342-d101-4396-b90e-665be5a6eacb?context=eyJkc1BvcnRhbElkIjoiY2QxYTBjNDEtYTUwNS00NjQyLWJiN2UtYTdhMjc4NjViYmZmIn0=#section-header-13)[](https://docs.google.com/document/d/1z6e2nDV9zIWKqCLQepPpgb0xhXuNKh2i/edit#heading=h.bhfp3d99k8ra) above. Requests may be submitted by Authorized Agents as described in [Your Privacy Choices](#otnotice-section-7a345332-a714-4524-a7e2-0f6bb5e9485e)[](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/policies/a8797342-d101-4396-b90e-665be5a6eacb?context=eyJkc1BvcnRhbElkIjoiY2QxYTBjNDEtYTUwNS00NjQyLWJiN2UtYTdhMjc4NjViYmZmIn0=#section-header-13)[](https://docs.google.com/document/d/1z6e2nDV9zIWKqCLQepPpgb0xhXuNKh2i/edit#heading=h.bhfp3d99k8ra). If you believe that applicable data protection laws have not been complied with, you may lodge an appeal with us by using the contact information provided [below](#otnotice-section-a57c72e4-400e-4d51-8f82-be2f74ffa5eb). You also have the right to complain directly to the appropriate data protection authority.

17\. Changes to this Privacy Policy
-----------------------------------

We may occasionally update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes in our practices with respect to the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information and/or changes in applicable law. 

The “Last updated” date at the top of this page indicates when this Privacy Policy was last revised. If we make changes, we will revise the date at the top of this Privacy Policy and, in the case of material changes to this Privacy Policy, we may provide you with additional notice (such as a notice posted on the Services or a message delivered to the email address that we have on file for you), and seek your consent where required by applicable privacy laws.

We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy periodically to remain informed about our information handling and privacy practices.

18\. Contact Information
------------------------

Questions or comments about this Privacy Policy or our information handling practices? Contact Instacart’s Global Privacy Team at:  

Instacart

50 Beale Street, Suite 600

San Francisco, California 94105

1-888-246-7822  

For customer service inquiries, visit our [Help Center](https://www.instacart.com/help).

If you have a disability and would like to access this Privacy Policy in an alternative format, please contact us at (888) 317-8968. Instacart is committed to making its electronic and information technologies accessible to individuals with disabilities.

If you have comments concerning this website’s accessibility, please contact us at the email address [accessibility-feedback@instacart.com](mailto:accessibility-feedback@instacart.com).
